<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EmberQuill's Blog</title><link>https://emberquill.com/</link><description>Recent content on EmberQuill's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 20:45:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emberquill.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading Data From Pokemon ROMs</title><link>https://emberquill.com/posts/reading-data-from-pokemon-roms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 20:45:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://emberquill.com/posts/reading-data-from-pokemon-roms/</guid><description>This is going to be a long one. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Pokemon ROM hacking.
First, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what a ROM hack is, basically it&amp;rsquo;s just a modified or &amp;ldquo;hacked&amp;rdquo; game. Not necessarily for the sake of cheating, though, which is what usually comes to mind when someone talks about hacked games. In fact, many ROM hacks are significantly more difficult than the original games they&amp;rsquo;re based on. ROM hacks exist for many reasons, but that&amp;rsquo;s not really the point of this post so if you really want to learn more, Bulbapedia has a great article on the subject.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://emberquill.com/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:12:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://emberquill.com/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a hobbyist computer programmer for over 2 decades now, and doing it professionally for about 7 years. Despite all that, I&amp;rsquo;m still flying by the seat of my pants and figuring it out as I go along.
Normally people would list all of their impressive achievements and interesting facts, but I actually don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot to say here.
What I Do I&amp;rsquo;m a Cloud Systems Engineer for a Fortune 500 company, which means that my main job is to do the work of about seven people by keeping our company&amp;rsquo;s cloud infrastructure, a Lovecraftian horror that has sunk its tendrils into into AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, and who knows what else, from collapsing and dragging the entire company down with it.</description></item><item><title>New Site</title><link>https://emberquill.com/posts/new-site/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 20:41:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://emberquill.com/posts/new-site/</guid><description>Trying this again, apparently.
Back in mid-2020, I decided to set up a blog. I set up a GitHub Pages site, a build pipeline to generate my static site with Hugo, and wrote my first post. And then I never updated my blog again, and eventually deleted it outright. But now I&amp;rsquo;m making another attempt.
But why? I want to talk about stuff. Seriously, that&amp;rsquo;s it. I started a bigger-than-anticipated project involving Pokemon GBA ROM hacking (more on that in a future post) and realized that I really wanted to talk about what I was doing and the headaches I ran into trying to decipher the data structures in a Pokemon Emerald cartridge dump.</description></item></channel></rss>